Are you ready?
いいですか。
Hi. Hi.
こんにちは
I'm Michelle. I'm Sarah. Nice to meet you.
ミチェルです。サラです。よろしくお願いします。
So I’m just going to briefly explain about this task,
タスクの説明をします
so I'm going to be the moderator today for this task
今回は私が担当します
And today we will be conducting the interview with the GPS system.
そしてGPSに関してのインタビューを行います
Okay
はい
Which is on the right side of you
右側にある機能です
On each task you will have a scenario and mission to do with the GPS system
タスクごとにシナリオとミッションがあります
Okay.
はい
So while doing the mission, you can say a lot of your thoughts or concerns.
タスクをやっているときに意見や提案を教えてくださると
It will help for us to do our system.
助かります
Okay.
はい
So okay.
And we have there is an interpreter who
電話越しで
interprets what you say, in a conference call.
内容を受け取っています
So I might give you a sign to
何かを言って欲しいときには
say something
教えます
okay.
はい
So for now you will have 2 minutes
まず２分間の
for test driving. Please drive
テストドライブを行います
right now?
今ですか。
Yes. The brake is the
はい、ブレーキは
middle one
真ん中にあります
and the steering wheel is very sensitive so be careful
ハンドルがとても敏感なので気をつけてください
keep your speed
速度も保ってください
You have 2 minutes
２分間です
Okay, so.
では
Okay, so from now on, I'm going to ask you about the suggestion card on the screen.
画面に表示されているサジェスションカードについて聞きます
Can you find it? Yeah over here. Right.
どこにあるか分かりますか。ここです。はい。
So before
まず
doing it, we're just going to stop the music
音楽を止めます
So actually that was the first task.
これが最初のタスクでした
While you're driving the first task was doing it.
運転するのが最初のタスクでした
Did you notice updates of this suggestion card? Yes.
サジェスションカードのアップデートに気づきましたか。はい。
Oh, yes.
そうですか
Okay.
はい
Like different things would pop up while I was driving
運転中に様々なものが表示されていました
Yeah. Okay.
はい
So while
これは
driving were the updates bothering you?
邪魔でしたか
A little bit.
はい、少し
Okay. Not really though.
それほどでもありませんが
Can you score 1 to 7?
１−７で評価してください
Like a one. One.
１ですね
How about
えっと
Okay so extremely bothered is one
とても邪魔だったが１です
Oh. Okay.
はい
Extremely comfortable is seven.
邪魔ではないが７です
So it could be seven? Yeah. Like a seven.
７ですか。はい、７ですね。
and
そして
And can you tell me why you gave this score?
理由を教えてください
Because it didn't really bother me like I noticed it,
変化に気づきましたが
but it wasn't like bothering my driving.
特に邪魔と感じなかったので
Okay, so.
はい
Okay, now you don't drive
これから運転はしなくて大丈夫ですが
but I might ask you to imagine that you're driving.
運転している想像をしてもらいます
Okay, so let's try it.
やってみましょう
So let's imagine that you're driving.
運転していると想像してください
So it might be helpful
ハンドルを握って画面に集中すると
You can you put your hands on the wheel and your eyes on the screen.
やりやすいかもしれません
Okay.
はい
So let's say I'm going to give you a scenario.
シナリオを提示します
You are going home for your party
家で行われているパーティーに向かっています
but you've noticed that you are running out of gas.
ですがガソリンがないことに気づきます
So you want to go to Chevron Gas Station that you went to yesterday
なので昨日行ったシェブロンガスステーションに行きたいと思います
here we're going to use this “navigation to Chevron
サジェスションの３つ目の項目「ガスステーションへナビ」の
Gas Station” card which is the third one on the suggestion.
カードを使用します
Yes. Before tapping it,
タップする前に
can you
何が
expect what's going to be on the screen?
何が予想されますか。
Your expectation? Like the GPS? Yes
GPSのですか。はい。
It’s going to show me where to go and how to go with the directions.
経路と目的地を表示すると思います
Do I tap it?
タップしていいですか。
Oh, no, no.
いいえ
I need to type your answer so please wait.
返答を入力しないといけないので
Oh, okay.
はい
Now please tap
ではタップしてください
Okay, let's go.
行きましょう
Okay. Yeah, that's what I was expecting.
予想通りです
Okay, so after tapping the card is it any different
予想外だったことは
from your expectation?
ありますか。
I mean, no, it's pretty similar.
いいえ、似ています
It's just like this is normally, like, a little thicker but it's the same.
普段と一緒です。ただ他のやつはアイコンが大きめです。
It tells you the arrival, tells you how long it’s
到着時間と目的地への時間を表示しています
going to take. The only thing
ただ
it's not telling me is how many miles away it is
距離が表示されていません
because normally it's like on the bottom, how many miles the drive is.
大体、下の方に表示されているのですが
Right.
はい
But it's not telling me that.
ですが書いてません
Okay.
はい
So for this one, how difficult or easy was this task to complete?
このタスクの難易度を１−７で評価してください。
1-7. Seven is easy?
７が簡単ですよね？
Seven is pretty easy. Okay.
７が簡単です。はい。
And can you tell me the reason?
理由を教えてください
Because it was like you press it
押すだけで
and then, nothing complicated about it.
難しいところはありませんでした
Yeah. So
はい
after
では
filling up the gas, you got into your car
給油した後、乗車しました
Mm hmm.
はい
Now you're ready to
帰宅する
Ready to go home for your party.
準備万全です
So here we're going to use “start navigation” card in this suggestion card.
サジェスションカードの「ナビを開始」のカードを使用します
Okay, so before tapping the card, can you expect what's going to happen?
タップする前に何が予想されますか。
Same thing as before.
先ほどと同様に
You're going to have the arrows.
矢印が表示され
Tell you what time we'll be home.
到着時刻を表示すると思います
In the map?
地図の中ですか。
In the map? In the map.
はい、地図の中に
Yeah.
はい
Okay. Can you tap? Yeah.
タップしてください
What I expected.
予想通りです
Okay.
はい
All right.
では
So after tapping the card,
予想外だった
how is it different from your expectation?
ことはありましたか。
It's not.
いいえ
It's the same?
一緒ですか。
Yeah.
はい
Can you score it
１−７で評価して
1-7
ください
Seven, seven.
７ですね
And can you tell me the reason?
理由を教えてください。
Because there's nothing difficult about it.
難しい点はありませんでした
It wasn't a complicated task.
タスク自体も簡単でした
Okay, so next one.
進みます
So imagine that you are driving.
運転していると仮定します
for your party.
家のパーティーに向かっています
Oh, here we're going to use the “play some music” card.
「音楽を流す」のカードを使用します
Okay.
はい
So before
では
okay, so
はい
we are going to use the “play some music” card. Before tapping that
タップする前に
can you tell me your expectation?
何が予想されますか
Oh yeah.
はい
It's going to have like the song name and with the little arrows.
曲の名前と矢印が出てくると思います
That's what I like. Yeah.
好きなので
And then it's going to play the music. Right away?
そして音楽が流れると思います。すぐですか。
Yeah, right away.
はい、すぐです
I mean, I feel like I’d have to pick a song, right?
曲を選ばないといけないと思いますが
But I don't know if you guys have a song already set in “play
それかもうすでに曲が
music” or not.
入っているのか知りませんが
Okay.
はい
So can you tap on it? Yes.
タップしてください。はい。
Okay, I got it.
了解です
Yeah.
はい
So after tapping the music that you were listening to
タップした後
during the 2 minute simulation was continued
2分のシミュレーションで流れていた曲が再生されました
So after tapping the card, how is it different from your expectation?
予想外だったことはありますか。
Well, it didn't pop up the like the song name and the title and anything.
曲の名前やリストが表示されませんでした
Yeah, a little different from what I expected.
少し予想と異なりました
Because in my car it pops up
私の車だと出てくるので
1-7, can you score it?
１−７で評価してください
Seven, nothing hard about the task.
７ですね、難しいタスクではありません
Right.
はい
So again you are still driving, let’s imagine that
運転中だとします
so here we're going to use the “send a message” card.
「メッセージを送信する」カードを使用します
Okay.
はい
So before tapping the card, can you tell me your expectation?
タップする前に何が予想されますか
The message box, maybe.
メッセージボックスだと思います
Message box
メッセージボックスですね
Mm
はい
Or maybe like the little Siri icon.
小さいSiriのアイコンや
Siri icon. Maybe yeah.
Siriのアイコン。はい。
Not sure.
分かりませんが。
Okay.
はい
So here I'm going to give you a scenario which is,
シナリオを提示します
you are going to send a message to your brother, Jonathan.
兄弟のジョナサンにメッセージを送ってもらいます
Okay. That you will be arriving in 30 minutes.
30分後に着くと連絡してください
Okay. Okay.
はい
Can you try to tap on the card? Yes
タップしてください。はい。
Who do you want to message?
誰宛のメッセージですか。
Jonathan
ジョナサン
Sure. What's the message?
メッセージの内容は何ですか
I will arrive in 30 minutes.
30分後に着きます
Sending your message.
送信中です
Okay.
はい
So after tapping the card, how is it different from your expectation?
予想外だったことはありますか
Um, it was better.
良かったです
In my car
私の車は
It's really hard. It's not that clear.
困難で、はっきりしていません
It's like, misinterprets what I say a lot.
誤字をよく犯します
But this one interpreted it very clearly. Okay.
これははっきり聞き取ってくれました
Apart from voice recognition
音声を聞き取る以外に
Is there anything different from your expectation?
予想外だったことはありますか
Just like the icon?
アイコンと
And I didn't expect it
予想外だったのは
to like write out what I said because it doesn't normally do that.
言ってことを表示するところです
Okay.
はい
that's
これは
okay.
はい
Before we move on,
進む前に
let’s reboot the system.
再起動します
So for the message function, how difficult or easy was the task?
このメッセージ機能の難易度を評価してください
Seven. Seven.
７ですね
And can you tell me the reason?
理由を教えてください。
It was easy.
簡単でした
There was nothing hard about it.
難しいところはありませんでした
Okay. So
はい
let's imagine again that you are still driving.
運転中だと仮定します
So you got almost home
後少しで帰宅ですが
and you noticed that you left a document that you need for tomorrow’s meeting.
明日のミーティングに必要な書類を忘れてしまいました
So you want to go back to your office.
職場に戻らなくてはいけません
So here we're going to use “navigate to work” card.
「職場へナビ」のカードを使用します
Okay.
はい
Well, before that, before tapping the card
タップする前に
can you expect what will happen?
何が予想できますか
Yeah the same as the other two navigation buttons, the map and
他２つのナビのボタンと同様に
the time.
地図と時間が出てくると思います
Okay so can you tap
タップしてください
Okay
はい
Let's go.
行きましょう
Yeah what I expected
予想通りです
Okay.
はい
Is
では
Is there any difference?
予想外だったことはありますか
No.
いいえ
And can you give me the score?
評価してください
Yeah. Seven, seven.
７ですね
It wasn't hard to do.
難しくありませんでした
Okay,
はい
so next you are still driving
まだ運転中です
and on the way to your office
職場に向かっているので
you want to play some music
音楽を流したいと思います
with Spotify.
スポティファイを使って
Okay. Okay.
はい
So we're going to use “play some music” card on the suggestions.
「音楽を流す」のカードを使用します
Okay.
はい
So before tapping the card, what is your expectation?
タップする前に何が予想されますか
A list of music.
曲のリストです
曲のリストですね
Okay.
はい
So can you tap on the “play some music” card to listen to the music?
「音楽を流す」を押してください
All right.
はい
I can play that on Spotify, YouTube music or Amazon music.
スポティファイ、YouTubeミュージック、アマゾンミュージックで聴けます
Which one do you want to use?
どれを開きますか
Spotify
スポティファイ
Ok play on
スポティファイを
Spotify
開きます
Okay. The music’s on.
音楽が流れました
Yeah.
はい
Okay.
Let’s stop the music
音楽を止めます
So Spotify randomly chose the music for you.
スポティファイがランダムで音楽を選びました
Oh. Okay.
はい
So after tapping the card, how is it different from your expectation?
予想外だったことはありますか
I thought that if I said “play some music”, it would give me a list of music.
曲のリストが表示されると思っていました
But then it gave me three options where to play music.
ですが３つのアプリのうちどれを使用したいかを聞かれました
And for Spotify, it was random
スポティファイはランダムで曲を流しました
Alright
はい
So can you score from 1 to 7?
１−７で評価してください
Maybe six.
６ですね
There were more steps involved.
手順が多かったと感じます
手順が多かったのですね
It wasn't as simple as just play some music
音楽を流すだけにしては単純ではありませんでした
okay.
はい
Next one is “how can I help”
次は「ご用件をお聞きします」のカード
card
です
Okay.
はい
So we're going to use that card. Before tapping the card
タップする前に何が
What is your expectation?
予想できますか
I think there's going to be a voice and it's going to say, “how can I help you”?
音声コマンドが「ご用件をお聞きします」と言い
And then I have to verbally give my, what I need
返答する形式だと
help with.
思います
I’m going to give you a scenario for this task
シナリオを提示します
So your car is in parking, your car’s parked.
駐車中だと仮定します
Okay.
はい
And you you've just arrived at home, but you've noticed
帰宅しましたが
that you forgot to buy something from Whole Foods.
スーパーでの買い忘れに気づきました
Okay, so you want to go to Whole Foods
なのでスーパーに行かないといけません
Can you tap on it to go to Whole Foods?
スーパーに行くためにタップしてください
Do I tap on the “How can I help”?
「ご用件をお聞きします」のカードですか。
Yes.
はい
Whole Foods?
スーパーへ
Sure.
もちろん
Navigation
スーパーへ
to Whole Foods.
ナビします
Okay.
はい
It's actually after you were saying it's going to be showing the Whole Foods. Oh.
実際は言って後に「スーパー」と表示されます
Right.
はい
Okay.
So after tapping the card, how is it different?
予想外だったことはありますか
Um, it didn't ask me
「ご用件をお聞きします」と
“How can I help?” which is interesting.
聞かなかったことに驚きました
Just sound?
音だけだったことですか
Yeah.
はい
So can you give me the score? Six
評価してください。６ですね。
And the reason is?
理由を教えてください。
Um, easy.
簡単でした
Easy?
簡単？
Yeah, it wasn't hard.
難しくありませんでした
I'm sorry the conference call
すみません電話が
is coming here
くるみたいです
Okay.
はい
So. Okay, so
では
this GPS system,
GPSシステムには
it has profiling features
プロファイリング機能があります
like calendar, playlist, like that.
カレンダー、プレイリストなど
But in order to activate the function (calendar, playlist),
ですがこのような機能を使用するには
you need to sign in first, such as Google, Apple, Amazon account.
Google, Apple, Amazonのアカウトでサインインしないといけません
So personal account.
個人のアカウントです
So we're going to use the “sign in for more features” card.
「サインインして他の機能を使う」のカードを使用します
Okay.
はい
Before tapping the card, what is your information?
タップする前に何が予想されますか。
Um, like the box that has username and in a box
ユーザーネームとパスワードを入力する
that has password.
ボックスが出てくると思います
Or maybe, I don't know, it looks like it's a verbal, so maybe it'll ask me
それか声で入力するのかもしれません
which account it wants to sign in and maybe my information is saved.
事前に登録した情報をもとに
So it's going to just sign into the account that I want.
サインインしたいアカウントを選ぶなど
Okay. Can you try to tap on it?
タップしてください
Okay, I
はい
got it.
了解です
Sign in with phone
携帯でサインインする
Oh do I have to tap on it?
押すのですか。
Oh, no, it's not going to be activated.
いいえ、反応しません
But this is the screen.
ですがこれが画面です
Oh, okay. After you tap the card. Oh, I see.
カードをタップした後
Okay, so after tapping the card how is it different?
予想外だったことはありますか
Um, it's not,
例えば
I guess I wasn't expecting two different options.
２つの選択肢が表示されると思っていませんでした
Can you score this from 1-7?
１−７で評価してください
Seven.
７ですね
Yeah, it's a simple task.
単純なタスクでした
Because it's simple?
単純だからですか。
Yeah.
はい
I mean, most of these are simple, just like pressing something,
単純なタスクばかりです。押したり、
saying something, nothing super complicated.
言ったり、難しくありません
How I would do everyday when I'm driving
運転中に出ることです
Okay, let’s move on.
進みます
So from now on, I'm going to ask you about the suggestion card layout
サジェスションカードのレイアウトに関して質問します
we have four types of suggestion card layouts
4種のレイアウトがあります
and I need your personal opinions
個人的な感想を聞かせてください
So we have a type A to D
タイプAからDまであります
So the one that you are looking looking at is type A.
現在閲覧しているのがタイプAです
Okay, so type A, how is the icon
タイプAのアイコンや
and sentence of the suggestion card, easy to read?
文字は読みやすいですか。
It's pretty easy to read. Is it seven?
読みやすいです。７ですか。
Yes, seven. Maybe it's seven.
多分７ですね。
Can you tell me the reason?
理由を教えてください。
Oh because the words are big like it's a big font
文字やフォントが大きく
it easy to read, it's not too small.
小さすぎず、読みやすいです
So like when you're driving you don't have to squint to read the screen.
運転中でも斜視しなくても見えます
Was the suggestion card
サジェスションカードは
easy to reach and select?
操作しやすかったですか
Yeah. 1-7?
１−７で評価してください
Seven.
７ですね
And can you tell me why you gave this score?
理由を教えてください。
Because it’s easy to reach and select
手を伸ばして選びやすかったです
Okay.
はい
Now I'm going to show you four types from A to D
タイプAからDを表示します
So those are our layouts.
これらがレイアウトです
the suggestion cards
サジェスションカードの
Can you rank
気に入った順で
from best to worst?
ランク付けしてください
All of them.
全てを
A would probably be the best, D would be the worst.
Aが一番気に入り、Dが一番気に入りません
Okay. And how about the B and C?
BとCはどうですか。
C is right after A, so that would be second and then
Aの次にC、そして
B would be third.
Bが3番目です
So is it ACBD?
ACBDの順ですね
Okay, for type A,
ではタイプAの
so this is type A, what do you like about this card?
どこが気に入りましたか
It is easy to read.
読みやすいです
It gives you three suggestions and it also gives you detail.
３つのサジェスションを出してくれるのと、詳細まで載っています
Like it'll tell you, oh, you know, “12 minutes via this route”
例えば「このルートだと12分」など
Okay.
はい
Yeah.
How about dislike parts of this card?
気に入らない部分はどこですか
I don't have any.
ないです
Okay.
はい
And the second one is type C.
次はタイプCです
So what do you like about this one?
どこが気に入りましたか
Same thing. There's three
同様に３つの選択肢があるのと
options. It's clear.
はっきりしています
Easy to read. It's big.
読みやすく、文字が大きいです
The font is easy to read from like far away.
フォントも遠くから読めます
While you're driving
運転中でも
Do you have any dislikes?
気に入らない部分はありますか
So yeah.
はい
I guess if they would give the minute to work it would be helpful.
職場まで何分かかるのかを表示していたら良かったと思います
It would be nice to know
知りたいので
because like before I click it, if it's already giving me
クリックした時に
like an estimate, that's the best.
大体の時間が分かるといいです
So next one is type B
次はタイプBです
what do you like about this one?
どこが気に入りましたか
I don't really like it, but I guess it's like it's smaller.
好きではないですが、小さめなので
I like how at least there's three features like it gives you three options
３つの選択肢を
all at once.
一気に見ることができます
You don't have to go looking for the third one.
３つ目の項目を探さなくても大丈夫です
Small though, so  while driving that might be kind of
ですが小さいので運転中は読みにくいかもしれません
You mean the size?
サイズですか。
The font size is small
フォントが小さいです
Okay so the last one is type D
最後はタイプDです
what do you like about this one?
どこが気に入りましたか
It's big, easy you read.
大きくて、読みやすいです
I don't like that there's only two suggestions.
２つのサジェスションしかないのが嫌です
Yeah, I mean, I have to go look for the third one.
３つ目の項目を探さないといけないので
That's not good
良くないです
while driving.
運転中は
so the first session is almost done.
もう少しで最初のセッションが終了します
We have only two questions.
２つの質問だけです
So overall,
全体的に
how would you recommend this feature?
この機能をお勧めすると思いますか
I guess like, um, like out of what?
評価の基準はなんですか。
All of them. No like give me like a ranking.
全てです。いいえ、評価の基準です。
Oh, 1-10. I guess maybe like a seven,
１−１０です。７ですね。
seven.
７ですね
Okay. And can you tell me the reason?
理由を教えてください。
It's pretty simple and easy to use,
単純で使いやすいですが
but I feel like for the certain voice assistant, it would be nice if it said, “Hi
音声コマンドで「ご用件をお聞きします」と言ってくれた方が
How can I help you?” and then, yeah
いいと思いました
Okay.
はい
Yeah, that's like the one thing I don't like.
唯一気に入らなかった部分です
Okay, so the first session is over.
これで最初のセッションは終了です
Okay, uh, before the second one, do you need a break?
次のセッションの前に休みを挟みますか。
No I’m okay
大丈夫です
Okay, so we're just.
では